翻译: 堇耶 研习嘲讽多年 元气
朋友们 你们好啊
Bonjour, mes amis.
看来有人在巴黎过得不错呀
Oh, someone had a good time in Paris.
校对: 番茄滚滚
对 我和Kevin开心极了
Oh, Kevin and I shared a perfect week together.
感觉像是躺在牛角面包上一样
I feel like I'm floating on a croissant.
后期: 天灵没有盖
我想知道为什么人们不多唱唱歌呢
I wonder why people don't just break into song more often.
我都跟你申请了几个月了
I've been asking you for months if I could
压制: 怪查理
我能不能这样接电话
answer the phone like,
尽管试试吧
Give it a whirl, girl.
嗨 他说话押韵
Guys, he's rhyming.
还让Gina唱歌了
He's telling Gina to sing.
Holt警监在假期玩嗨了
Captain Holt is on a vacation high!
现在说什么他都会答应的
He will say yes to anything right now.
我想要一匹警用马
I would like a police horse,
然后让Terry一直骑在上面
and I'd like Terry to be riding it almost constantly.
我想找个负责人力资源的来提醒下各位
I'd like an HR person to remind everyone
什么叫办公室规则
about workplace boundaries.
有种日本产的马桶圈
The Japanese make toilet seats
它会射出一股温水 就射在你的
which squirt a heated jet of water right up your...
停 别说下去了
I'm gonna stop you right there, bud.
我们需要的是一辆装甲运兵车
What we need in here is an armored personnel carrier...
一辆坦克
a tank!
两辆 我也要
Two tanks. I want a tank too.
没问题 一人一辆坦克
Great, so everyone gets a tank.
记得不能坏了Holt警监的假后好心情
Just remember we can't ruin Captain Holt's vacation high,
所以谁都不能惹他生气
so no one say anything that'll upset him.
噢 不 那两个白痴在那干嘛
Oh, no, what are those morons doing in there?
可能没那么糟 也许他们没惹警监生气
Maybe it's not that bad; maybe they didn't upset him.
你们干了什么 说了什么
What'd you do? What'd you say?
没什么 我们只是欢迎警监回来
Nothing. We just said, "Welcome back."
然后一起笑了笑他新长出来的肥肉
And laughed with him about all the weight he gained in France.
不
No!
都站在这儿干什么
Why is everyone just standing around?
干活去
Get back to work!
再见了 我的坦克
So long, tank.
坦克
Tank?
我在巴黎胖了三磅
I gained three pounds in Paris...
三磅啊
three pounds!
神烦警探
第三季 第十九集
电波诚译
Terry 有你的快递
Hey, Terry, I have a package for you.
噢 警长大人收到礼物了
Ooh, Sarge got a present.
"箱子里是什么"
"What's in the box?"
布拉德 皮特 "七宗罪"
Brad Pitt, "Se7en."
不过说真的 箱子里是什么
But seriously, what's in the box?
世界上最糟糕的东西
The worst thing in the world.
闭嘴 蠢货
Shut up, stupid.
谁寄给你只小猫
Okay, so who sent you a kitten
还有你为什么这么讨厌它
and why do you hate it?
这不是一只小猫
It's not a kitten.
这是在扇我的脸啊
It's a slap in the face
因为二十年前的某件事
for something that happened 20 years ago.
就是你还是平顶头的时候吗
When you had a flat top?
我知道你剪过平顶头
I know you had a flat top,
因为见过照片
'cause I saw pictures.
抱歉 继续吧 平顶头Terry
Sorry, go on with your story, Flat Top Terry.
那是1995年
It was 1995.
我刚刚成为警探
I'd just made detective.
第一天去6-5区的时候特别兴奋
I was really excited about my first day at the 6-5,
但警队里都是一群混蛋
but the guys in the squad were a bunch of jerks.
嗨 我是Terry
Hi, I'm Terry.
我的办公桌在哪呀
Which desk is mine?
破个案子
Solve a case,
你就有办公桌了
then you get a desk.
像这样的事还有很多
They were like that about a lot of stuff.
破个案子 你才有咖啡喝
Whoa, solve a case, then you get coffee.
破个案子 你才能在给Debbie的生日卡上签名
Solve a case, then you can sign Debbie's birthday card.
听起来你似乎得破个案子
Sounds like you needed to solve a case.
是这样 所以我选了个最难的
Exactly, so I picked the biggest one I could find:
一起连环入室盗窃案 全都是一样的作案手法
a string of B&Es,all with the same M.O.
案犯从高层建筑的窗户爬进去
Guy climbed in through high-rise windows.
一个月之后 我发现了嫌犯
After a month, I found my suspect:
Dmitri Kuzkho
Dmitri Kuzkho.
有犯罪记录的前杂技演员
Ex-acrobat with a criminal record.
马戏团人渣 一定是他
Circus trash! It has to be him.
我也是这么说的
That's exactly what I said.
马戏团人渣 一定是他
Circus trash! It has to be him.
我追查那个杂技演员
I tracked down my acrobat,
让特警包围他住的地方
got SWAT to surround his building.
一切都完美极了
There was no way anything could go wrong.
纽约警察局 趴下
NYPD! Down!
趴到地上
Get on the ground!
举起手来
Let's see your hands!
啊噢
Uh-oh.
那家伙两年前从高空秋千上摔了下来
My guy had a terrible trapeze fall two years prior...
他的脊椎被摔成了两半
snapped his spine in half.
但这跟小猫有什么关系
So why the kitten?
那种情况下
Well, in the moment,
我当时可能有点慌乱
I may have gotten a little flustered.
看 他养了只猫
Look, he's got a cat!
他肯定是把猫训练成盗窃犯
He trained the cat to do the robberies!
所以人们都叫他们"毛"贼
That's why they call them cat burglars!
怎么没人说话
Why is no one saying anything?
噢 Terry
Oh, Terry.
他们寄只猫给我是为了提醒我那件事 顺便打我的脸
Yeah, now they send me cats to remind me of that day and rub it in my face.
我得在网上登个广告
I'm gonna go put a ad online
找人收养这个可恶的小粪球
so I can find someone to adopt this evil, little turd.
对比一下的话
Counterpoint:
你们两只看起来还挺可爱的
you two make an adorable couple.
我建议把它放到杯子里
Might I suggest putting him in a mug
然后装作要喝一口的样子
and pretending to take a sip?
Terry你这么急着走是要照我说的做吗
Terry, are you stomping off to do my thing?
能让我用用你的手机吗
Oh, hey, can I borrow that?
Genevieve去外地了
Genevieve's out of town.
我需要两个手机 一个发"前面" 一个发"后面"
I need two phones so I can send her a "Frontie" And a "Backie."
我可不想看见你的屁股出现在我的云相册里
I don't want your ass in my cloud.
Adrian 你住在休息室吗
Adrian, are you living in the break room?
没啊 怎么这么问
No, why do you ask?
因为你在我们吃饭的桌子旁 给肩膀除毛
Uh, because you're shaving your shoulder in our communal eating space;
而且你在沙发上搭了个床
you have a bed set up on the couch;
诸如此类
stuff like that.
好吧 被逮到了
Fine. Busted.
就因为我那个蠢邻居受不了那么一点点
My landlord kicked me out because my stupid neighbors
夜里的尖叫声 所以房东把我赶出来了
couldn't handle a few tiny night screams.
我梦到有人要用削尖的 水果挖勺
I was dreaming that someone was trying to scalp me
剥我的头皮
with a sharpened grapefruit spoon.
人脑真是神奇
Aren't brains fascinating?
我是说 怎么能梦到这么奇怪的事情
I mean, where does it come up with this stuff?
我卧底的时候确实有人试图用
When I was undercover, someone did try and scalp me
削尖的 水果挖勺剥我的头皮
with a sharpened grapefruit spoon.
好吧 这也有可能
Sure, that would do it.
你不是在跟Rosa约会吗
Aren't you dating Rosa?
不能住她家吗
Can't you just stay with her?
嗯 我们最近打得火热
Oh, yeah, no, we're doing this really hot thing
还没跟对方说住址
where we haven't told each other where we live.
这让我们的床上游戏更带劲
Makes our sex play really erotic.
- 恶心  - 我知道了
- Barf. - I totally get that.
有什么能帮到你的地方记得跟我说
Well, you let me know if there's anything I can do.
好呀 那我就住你家吧
Oh, yes, I will stay at your home.
谢啦
Thank you.
什么 怎么回事
Me? What... how now?
你刚说想帮我不是吗
You just said you wanted to help.
除非你只是说着玩的
Oh, unless you weren't being serious,
那我也理解
which I would get.
也不是没被背叛过
I've been betrayed before.
比如 被那个拿水果挖勺的家伙
For instance, by the grapefruit spoon guy.
不不不 绝对不是
No, no, no, no, definitely.
你可以住我那
You could stay with me.
噢 Chuck你最好了
Oh! You're the best, Chuck!
谢啦
Thank you!
不过记得买个好点的耳塞
But for real, get yourself some good ear plugs,
因为其实我夜里叫得比我刚刚形容的吓人多了
because I really downplayed how horrible those night screams are.
好啦 待会见了 室友
All right, I'll see you later, roomie.
好吧
All right.
9-9区明天会主办一堂拆弹课
Attention the 9-9 will be hosting a bomb-defusing class tomorrow.
我强烈建议大家参加
I highly recommend attending.
高压状态下拆除引爆装置是对能力的最大考验
Defusing an explosive device is the ultimate test of skill under pressure.
生死一念间
And the stakes: life or death.
- 管饭吗  - 嗯
- Will lunch be provided? - Yes.
算上我们
Count us in.
还有人吗
Anyone else?
- 我  - 还有我
- I'm in. - Me too.
这个课听着好像"屌炸了"
This class sounds like "Da bomb."
如果你不认真点的话我宁愿你不要参加
I'd rather you didn't attend if you're not gonna take it seriously.
- 是  - 解散
- Yup. - Dismissed.
我一定会称霸明天那堂课
I'm gonna dominate that class.
你不可能绣了二十年十字绣还提高不了手臂的稳定性
You don't cross-stitch for 20 years without developing a steady hand.
喔 你真能吹啊
Wow, you really think that's a brag, don't you?
20块赌我比你强
20 bucks says I do better in that class than you do,
"线头"
thread-head.
好 来吧
All right, you're on.
另外我告诉你
And I'll have you know that
在缝纫界 "线头"可是个夸人的话
"Thread-head" is a glowing compliment in the sewing community.
你要是想骂我的话应该叫我漏针王
If you wanted to insult me, you should've called me a stitch skipper.
好 漏针王
Okay, stitch skipper.
喂 这还是我跟你说的
Oh, I handed it to you!
你最好看起来可爱点
You better look cute in this picture,
不然没人会想要你的
or no one's gonna want you.
快用你那蠢爪子做点什么
Do something with your damn paws!
喔 别激动 警长
Whoa, whoa, Sarge, relax.
我觉得你对这个恶作剧反应有点大
Look, I think you might be overreacting a little to this prank, and I should know.
说来你可能不信
You probably won't believe this, but
我高中时曾因为太帅而被人欺负
I was bullied in high school for being too handsome.
- 我不信  - 好吧
- I don't believe you. - You're right.
是因为手工课时把自己裤裆烧着了
It was for setting my crotch on fire in shop class.
可真疼死了
Hurt like the dickens.
重点是 有些人就是看什么都不顺眼 别理他们
Point is, haters gonna hate. Shake it off.
泰勒 斯威夫特 总是对的
Taylor Swift, always right.
那些霸凌者总找上我是因为我就跟一个霸凌者住在一起
The reason bullies get to me is because I lived with one...
我爸爸
my dad.
他是个特别冷血的人
He was a cruel man who didn't like his life,
因为讨厌自己的人生就要让我也过不好
and he took it out on me.
好
Okay, okay.
我们终于有进展了
Now we're getting somewhere.
如果你有父亲问题
If you're having dad problems,
那可是我的强项 兄弟
that's my jam, son.
谈起我爸感觉好奇怪
Real weird take on my crappy father.
你知道我跟我爸关系怎么转变的吗
You know how I turned the corner with my dad?
我直面他
I stood up to him,
这也是你应该对你爸做的事
and that's what you need to do with your dad.
不 他1988年就去世了
No, he died in 1988.
好吧 那就行不通了
Oh, okay, well, that probably won't work, then.
但这并不意味着你不能去6-5区
But it doesn't mean you can't go over to the 6-5
直面那些欺负你的人
and stand up to those bullies.
他们更会拿我开玩笑了
They'll just make fun of me more.
你在说什么啊 Terry
What are you talking about, Terry?
你体壮如牛
You are a human mountain.
光是耳朵上的肌肉就比我全身的都多
You have more muscles in your ears than I have in my entire body.
从没忘记锻炼耳朵
Never skip ear day, Jake.
你能空手碎金属
You can crush metal with your bare hands.
你能举起一辆公交车
You can lift a city bus.
你还能让你的胸弹来弹去
You can make your boobies do that bouncy thing.
这叫抖胸
They're called pecs.
一个意思
Same thing.
现在 去6-5区
Now, get on over to the 6-5
让那些混球把小猫收回去
and make those big jerks take back that tiny kitten.
好 没问题
Yeah. All right.
我去了
I'm doing it.
45分钟之后
没成功
Didn't work.
我又带了几只猫回来
I have more kittens than before.
什么 怎么回事
What? How?
早上好 警长
Morning, Sarge.
早上好
Oh, good morning,
小宝贝儿 小可爱们
my sweet, little cuties.
别叫它们小可爱
Don't call them cute.
如果它们聪明到会用武器一定会把我们都杀光的
They'd kill us all if they were smart enough to use weapons,
但是你们不聪明
but you're not smart.
你们很傻
You're dumb.
你们一直裸着 还在盒子里尿尿
You're always naked, and you pee in a box.
我觉得它们没有完全裸着
I suppose they're not totally naked
还有毛呢
with the fur.
总之 你记得20年前的案子你哪里做错了吗
Anyways, you know how you didn't solve that case 20 years ago?
谢谢你提醒我
Thanks for reminding me.
我还没提你把自己丁丁烧着的事
You don't see me bringing up how you burned your junk off.
没这回事
That didn't happen.
只是有点轻微的燎伤
There was just some light blistering.
重点是
The point is
那些恶霸能挑你刺的只有
the only thing those bullies have over you
那件你没破的案子
is that you never solved that case.
所以我们一起把它破了怎么样
So why don't we solve it together?
怎么做得到
How are we gonna do that?
我们潜进六五区
We'll sneak into the 6-5,
偷走那些旧档案
steal that old case file,
研究它直到找到那个窃贼
and work it till we find your burglar.
然后我们雄赳赳跑去那片警区
Then we march back into that precinct...
扯碎这几只猫崽
And we grind these kittens up
再塞进他们的喉咙
and shove them down their throats!
就是这样
Yes!
别听他瞎说
Don't listen to him.
你们是比你们伟大得多的东西的一部分
You're a part of something much bigger than yourselves.
早上好 Linetti
Well, good morning, Linetti.
我昨天晚上睡得像个婴儿
Whoo, I slept like a frickin' baby last night.
住在Chuck家简直像做梦
Staying at Chuck's is like a dream.
小个子就爱宠着我
Little guy loves doting on me,
但是 你还得去买些大点的内裤
although you're gonna need to buy some bigger underwear
万一我们要分着穿呢
if we're gonna be sharing, you know what I mean?
好 我去买
Okay, I'll get right on that.
好 拿着
Okay, cool. Here.
帮我看着点 好么
Take care of this for me, will you?
行
Yeah.
我去拿些糖当早饭
I'm gonna go get some breakfast candy.
好啊 过会儿见
Okay, catch you later.
所以 你和你新室友处得
So things are going really good
挺不错啊 看上去
with the new roomie, it seems.
太可怕了
It's horrible.
浴室里到处都是不知道是谁的血
There's someone's blood all over the bathroom.
他梦里掐了我的脖子两回
He sleep-choked me twice.
最糟的是 今天早上
And the worst part... this morning,
他吃光了我的麦片
he ate all of my cereal.
这是最糟的
That's the worst part?
那可是Nortfluskers牌的麦圈
They were Nortfluskers bran circles!
从奥斯陆海运来的
I had them shipped from Oslo.
哦 我真希望他滚蛋
Oh, I want him out.
但我太害怕了不敢告诉他
But I'm too scared to tell him.
好了 听着
All right, listen.
我知道你的精神动物
I know that your spirit animal
是只被踩扁了的毛虫
is a caterpillar that's been stepped on...
而我的是匹强大的狼
But mine is the mighty wolf.
如果你想打败狼王
And if you want to beat an alpha,
你就得先做狼王
you have to be an alpha.
不对哦
Wrongo.
如果当受气包当的好
If you're good enough at being a beta,
那狼王就会可怜你
then the alpha takes mercy on you
然后对你百依百顺
and ends up giving you what you want.
- Boyle  - 啊
- Boyle. - Argh!
你能别进你家厨房48小时左右么
Could you stay out of your kitchen for the next, like, 48 hours?
我要给我猎到的那只鹿剥皮
I'm gonna be skinning a deer that I shot.
啥玩意
What?
哦 再搭点塑料布
Ooh, and put up some of those plastic sheets.
我根本不知道我在干嘛
I have no idea what I'm doing.
- 好的  - 行 真棒
- Okay. - Okay, great.
- 聊得真开心 兄弟  - 是啊
- Good talk, buddy. - Yup.
我拿到档案了
I got the file.
哦 做得好 怎么办到的
Oh, nice work. How'd you do it?
这个嘛
Well...
管档案室的警长是位女士
the sergeant in charge of the file room was a lady,
所以我启动了Peralta的魅惑
so I just turned on the old Peralta charm.
你好啊
Hey, there.
有人在男厕所吐了
Some dude yarfed in the men's restroom.
你能找人去清理一下么
Could you please find somebody to clean that up?
Terry 根本没人吐
Terry, there was no yarf.
是啊 我想到了
Yeah, I figured that.
哦 好吧
Oh, okay.
看看我们拿到了什么
Let's see what we got here.
40张你站在轮椅男和他的猫旁边的照片
40 photos of you standing next to the guy in the wheelchair and his cat.
他们拍了一堆照 还做成了鼠标垫
They did a photoshoot. They made mouse pads.
这帮坏银
They are bad dudes.
好的 我们这样
All right, here's our plan.
我们去重访这案子的原始受害人
We are gonna re-interview all the original victims
从第一个开始
of this case, starting with the first one,
Janice McMinnion
Janice McMinnion.
额
Uh....
她12年前就死了
she died 12 years ago.
好 那就第二个
All right, the second one.
也死了
Also dead.
好 干嘛不直接跳到
Okay, why don't you just skip on down
第一个没死的人呢
to the first person that's not dead.
第八个
Number eight.
第八个 活着哦
Number eight, way to stay alive.
第八个 还活着
Number eight, still alive.
- 第八个 还活着  - 第八个 还活着
- Number eight, still alive. - Number eight, still alive.
先为前七个默哀
Moment of silence for the first seven, though.
好啦 出发
All right, let's go!
啊 有水银开关的压力炸弹
Ah, pressure bombs with mercury switches.
用手机做雷管的简易爆炸装置
IEDs with cell phone detonators.
哦 这是C4么
Oh, is that C4?
哦天 我们今天有些很厉害的炸弹哦
Oh, my, we've got some great bombs today, people.
欢迎
Welcome.
在这堂课上 我们会学习怎样处置
In this course, we'll be going over how to dispose
10种不同的爆炸装置
of 10 different types of explosive devices.
你今天所学能救了你和无数人的命
What you learn today could save your lives and countless others.
有问题么
Any questions?
会有排名或者计分系统来看出谁最棒吗
Yes, Will there be a grading or point system to see who's best?
在救人方面
At saving lives.
当然 在救人方面
Yes, at saving lives.
指的就是救人啦
Saving lives was always implied.
你们会被计时
Well, you will be timed.
- 完美  - 那就行
- Perfect. - That'll do.
但我建议忽视时间 专注在
But I would recommend ignoring the clock and focusing on...
是 是 是 你回答完问题了
Yeah, yeah, yeah, you answered the question.
速度点教我们
Hurry up and teach us.
嘿 老人家
Hey, Slowpoke.
等我们出去
When we get out of here,
我要给你绣个枕头上面写着"打脸"
I'm gonna needlepoint you a pillow that says, "Kapow."
嘿 Amy 你很烂
Hey, Amy. You suck.
哦 是么 你猜怎么着
Oh, yeah? Well, guess what?
枕头上还有很多地方
There's more room on that pillow...
长话短说 你还是烂
Real quick, before you finish: you still suck.
啊
Argh!
在这场废话里我比你动脑筋得多
I'm working so much harder than you on this trash talk,
我却是受伤的那个
and I'm the one whose feelings are getting hurt.
Santiago Diaz 够了
Santiago, Diaz... enough.
重点不在你们俩谁最快
This is not about who's fastest.
这是拆弹课堂
This is a bomb dismantling class.
我们是警员 不是在公园里下快棋的流浪儿
We are police officers, not street urchins playing speed chess in the park.
可耻啊
For shame.
好了 谢谢
All right, thanks.
好了 这是Esther记得的
Okay, here's what Esther remembers
她被盗的那晚发生的事
about the night that she was robbed.
她要么在饭店
She was either at a restaurant
要么在电影院 要么在做别的
or the movies or doing something else.
她要么是一个人 要么就和别人在一块
And she was either alone or with people.
她唯一确定的事是
The only thing she was absolutely sure of
我看着像个好人
is that I seem like a very nice boy,
这和案子无关
which is not relevant to the case,
但让我觉得开心
but did make me feel very good.
这太傻了
This is stupid.
过了20年
It was 20 years ago.
没人记得任何事
No one remembers anything.
我开始觉得也许我们该
I'm beginning to think maybe we should...
爬上那个窗台
Climb out on that ledge
看罪犯是怎么进来的
and see how the perp got in.
- 我想说放弃  - 什么
- I was gonna say give up. - What?
我想到这么惊艳的主意之后你还想放弃 Terry
Right after I came up with that incredible ledge thing, Terry?
我们在十楼 你受得了吗
We're 10 stories up. You can handle that?
警长 我不怕高 好么
Sarge, I'm not scared of heights, okay?
我怕蜜蜂 我怕蛇
I'm scared of bees, I'm scared of snakes,
我怕尼克斯队再也无法崛起
and I'm scared that the Knicks might never be good again,
但我不怕高
but I am not scared of heights.
我们要死了 我们要死了
We're gonna die! We're gonna die!
我们要死了
We're gonna die!
我感激你一辈子 如果你不告诉别人
I would appreciate it if you didn't tell anyone
我在窗台崩溃了
about my window ledge freak-out.
认为我们能在没有新线索的情况下
That's not as embarrassing as thinking we could actually solve
破掉一桩20年前的案子更丢人
a 20-year-old case with no new leads.
Terry 我们能破掉的 好么
Terry, we are gonna solve this, all right?
当然 可能我们今天做的一切工作
Sure, maybe none of the work we did today
没任何用处
led to any new information.
Jake
Jake...
而且 绝大多数案件都在
And sure, most crimes are solved
案发后48小时内解决
within the first 48 hours,
但是他们从不说说
but they never talk about the crimes
在案发后一亿个小时内破解的案子
that are solved within the first 100 million hours.
不 看这里
No, look at this.
1996年检查这个电梯的人叫Zerb Gudanya
The guy who inspected this elevator in 1996 was named Zerb Gudanya.
我们今天去的
That's the same weird name
四座大楼里所有电梯的检查员都叫这个怪名
who inspected the elevators in all four of the buildings we've been to today.
真的吗
Really?
Terry 有方向了
Terry, that's a lead.
我们有方向了
We have a lead!
We got a lead!
我们有方向了
我们要破案了
We're gonna solve this case.
我得去趟厕所
I have to use the bathroom.
I got to use the bathroom.
其实不用  我只是沉浸在这个节奏里
I actually don't; I just got in the rhythm of it.
那是Zerb Gudanya
There's Zerb Gudanya.
对一个电梯检查员来说这车也太奢侈了
Pretty fancy car for an elevator inspector.
俱乐部国际布莱顿海滩国际俱乐部
The Club International of Brighton Beach International Club?
"国际"和"俱乐部"都在出现了两次
"International" And "Club" Are both in the name twice.
Terry 这地方很低级
Terry, this place sleazy.
两项前科 超出常理的富有
Two priors, wealth beyond his means,
还能通过电梯井接近那些公寓
and he had access to the apartments through the elevator shaft.
他肯定是我们要找的人 出发
He has to be our guy. Let's go.
好的 我会说我是Ilya 一个来自莫斯科的商人
Okay, I'll say that I'm a businessman from Moscow named Ilya.
我卖雪地靴赚了几百万
"I make millions from selling snow boots."
就是想显摆下口音
That was more just to show off the accent.
才不是对雪地靴有特殊癖好呢
I'm not wedded to the snow boots thing.
喂 小伙子
Hey, fellas.
你们不会真的以为自己可以在6-5区搞小动作
You didn't really think that you could run an operation
不被我们发现吧
in the 6-5 without us finding out, did you?
根本没人吐了
There was no yarf.
这人好厉害
This guy's good.
Jake 这是我以前警队的同事 Holderton
Jake, this is Holderton from my old precinct.
你们到底在找什么
So who are you guys looking for in there?
虎斑猫
A Tabby?
还是暹罗猫
Siamese?
首先 我从没说过那只猫是盗窃犯
First of all, I never said the cat was a burglar.
我说的是它有可能是帮凶
I said he might be an accomplice.
你知道吗
You know what?
我真希望那个人是只猫
I hope the guy in there is a cat.
那就能让你好看了
That'll show you.
是啊 他是只猫就好抓多了
Yeah, if he was a cat, he'd be much easier to apprehend
而且估计也没什么危险了
and probably much less dangerous.
我们就是这么想的 走吧
That's what we think. Let's go.
我放弃了 我需要你的帮助
Okay, I give up. I need your help.
我要试试你的方法
I'm ready to try it your way.
你来得正是时候
Shh, you came at the perfect time.
他正在吃东西 动物吃东西的时候
He's eating, and when an animal eats,
正是它们最没有防备的时候
that's when they're at their most vulnerable.
你需要走过去
You need to get in there...
让他知道谁才是狼王
show him who the alpha is.
- 我需要起个狼的名字  - 好嘞
- I need a wolf name. - Yes.
Virginia Woolf 是位英国女作家 意识流文学代表人物 她的姓woolf与狼wolf发音相同
- Virginia Woolf  - 啥
- Virginia Woolf. - Huh?
我才不要当她那个人渣丈夫Leonard
Well, I'm not gonna be her lame husband, Leonard.
是时候了 Virginia
Okay, it's time, Virginia.
小兔崽子 咱们来谈谈
Hey, little man, let's talk about
你打算在我那儿呆多久吧
how much longer you're gonna stay at my place.
你在威胁我吗 Chuck
Are you threatening me, Chuck?
不敢不敢 长官
No, I'm not, sir.
我就想表达一下我有多欢迎你和我住一块儿
I just want to tell you how welcome you are to stay with me
永远永远永远
forever and ever and ever,
尊敬的大人
m'lord.
哈哈 好了
Ha! Okay.
很好 谢了
Good, thanks.
下次别搞得神神叨叨的
Next time don't be so weird about it.
如您所愿 祝好 长官
As you wish. Good day, sir.
还是很诡异
That's still weird.
好吧 抱歉
Hey，sorry.
你一点也不烂
You don't suck.
我也很抱歉
I'm sorry too.
我俩都说了伤感情的话
We both said hurtful things.
你没说 我好得很
You didn't. I was fine.
别再自欺欺人了
Well, now you're just lying to yourself.
但是Holt说得对
But Holt was right.
我们应该更严肃地对待这件事的
We should have taken this more seriously.
搞定
Done.
整整好两分钟 今日最快
Fastest time today by a full two minutes.
哇哦 我的妈呀
Whoo, mama!
这边一切都还好吗
Is everything okay over here?
嗯 好的不能再好了
Yes, couldn't be better,
因为我打败了这俩货
because I destroyed you both.
什么鬼
What the hell?
你不是说输赢不重要吗
I thought you said this wasn't about winning.
我这么说 是为了让你们做得慢一点
I did say that, so you would go slower
然后我就能赢了 也就是现在的结果
and I would win, which is what happened.
你跟我们一样好胜
You're just as competitive as we are.
胡扯 我比你们更好胜
Absurd. I'm more competitive.
现在谁 "屌炸"了
Now who's "Da bomb"?
你是怎么当上警长的
So what did they make you a sergeant for?
逮了个松果吗
Did you arrest a pine cone?
他过了笔试
He passed a written test,
就和别的警长一样
just like every other sergeant did.
你清楚得很
You knew that.
没啊 我在想他可能
Oh, no, I thought he might have gotten
因为逮了个松果
some kind of special promotion
而得到了特殊升职
from busting a pine cone.
你干嘛老提松果
Why do you keep bringing up pine cones?
根本不搭边儿
That's never been a part of this.
你懂个毛
You know what?
等着打脸吧
You're gonna eat your words,
因为警长就要把这案子破了
because Sarge is about to solve this case.
哪个案子 旧案还是松果那个
What, the old case or the pine cone one?
闭上你的嘴
You need to stop.
快看 我们要找的人Zerb就坐那儿
Look, our man Zerb is sitting right over there,
没错 他和所有的盗窃案都有关联
and yeah, he's connected to all of the robberies.
他异常可疑
And he's shady as hell.
看
Look.
服务员给了他一个暗号
Waiter just gave him a covert signal.
他站起来了
Now he's getting up.
他跟着那名服务员
Yeah, and now he's following said waiter
去下一个很可能是更可疑的地点
to a secondary, most likely even shadier spot.
有大事要发生了
Something's going on in there.
- 哦  - 没错了
- Huh. - Yeah, right... huh!
- 快 把他抓起来  - 快来
- Come on, let's go bust him! - Come on.
趴下  趴下
Down, down! Get down!
纽约警察
NYPD!
糟了
Uh-oh.
你在搞什么
What are you doing, man?
没什么 我胆固醇高
Nothing! I have high cholesterol!
我老婆说我不能吃红肉
My wife says I cannot have red meat,
所以他们就偷偷把炖牛肉给我
so they sneak in my beef stew.
求你了 别开枪
Please don't shoot.
天哪
Oh, my God.
又来了
It happened again.
只是这次这家伙是坐在马桶上
Only this guy's sitting on a toilet
不是轮椅上
instead of a wheelchair.
更蠢了
That's even more dumb.
过来 过来 Terry
Here, here, Terry.
靠近点才能把你照进去
Move in closer so I can get you in the photo.
怎么回事 Jake
What up, Jake?
这些崽子怎么从笼子里放出来了
Why are these dicks out of their cage?
我一夜没睡
I stayed up all night
看你的案子
working on your case,
Hans John和Nakatomi
and Hans, John, and Nakatomi
一直陪着我
made for great company.
我给他们起的都是<虎胆龙威>里的名字
I gave them all "Die Hard" Names.
我搞不懂你为什么
I don't understand why you wasted another night
又在这种解不开的案子上浪费一晚
on a case no one's ever gonna solve.
警长 我这会儿太困了
Sarge, I am way too sleep-deprived
没法抵抗你的消极态度
to deal with your negativity right now.
给你展示一下我的成果吧
Let me show you what I did.
我首先画了个布鲁克林1996年以来
I started off by making a map
所有的入室盗窃案的地图
of all of the burglaries that have gone down in Brooklyn
看看有没有规律
since 1996 to see if there was a pattern.
然后我发现了这个
That led me to this.
纽约犯罪太多
There is so much crime in New York.
根本不该住人
No one should live here.
不管怎么说 我在这问题上纠结了好几个小时
Anyways, I tripped out on that for a couple hours,
但是给在我连帽衫里
but I got cheered up
玩耍的小猫咪拍了张照后
after I took a picture of the kitties
我又精神焕发了
messing around in my little hoodie.
等会儿给你看
I'll show it to you later.
所以基本上 一晚上都浪费了
So basically, you wasted a whole night.
没有没有
No, no, no, my friend.
没有啦 因为然后我又埋头看你的资料了
No, no, no, 'cause then I dove back into your file
还发现了这个
and found this.
厉害 我人生的最低谷
Cool, the low point of my entire life.
警长 这张照片是1996年拍的
Sarge, this photo was taken in 1996.
你告诉我你要找的人两年前
You told me your guy broke his spine
摔断了脊椎骨 也就是1994年
two years before that, so '94.
仔细看他的运动鞋
Check out his sneakers.
95年的乔丹款
'95 Jordans.
在事故后一年才出的
They came out a year after the accident.
你看鞋底
Look at the soles.
全是泥
They're all muddy.
也就是说
Which means...
那贱人能走
That son of a bitch can walk!
- 正解  - 走吧
- Bingo. - Let's go!
好啦 猫咪小分队 集合
All right. Cat squad, assemble!
- 把猫留这儿  - 好的
- Leave the cats. - Okay.
Santiago Diaz 我想和你们
Santiago, Diaz, I wanted to talk to you
谈谈大家昨天在拆弹课程上的表现
about our performance in yesterday's bomb defusing course.
我们知道了 长官 你赢了
We know, sir. You won.
不 我们三个都没过
No, the three of us all failed.
很明显指导员认为
Apparently our instructor felt
我们对待课程不够严肃
we didn't take it seriously enough.
但是Hitchcock和Scully过了
But Hitchcock and Scully passed.
什么
What?
他们怎么可能拆得比我们好
How did they defuse bombs better than we did?
- 那些是炸弹  - 难以置信
- Those were bombs? - Unbelievable.
这是我们三个人的低谷
It's a low moment for us all.
我想教训就是我们不该
I think the lesson here is that we should not allow
让自己的好胜心影响工作之神圣
our competitiveness to interfere with the sanctity of our job.
完全同意 长官
Totally agree, sir.
不过
However,
下周末还有一堂精准驾驶课
there is a precision driving class next weekend.
- 最快完成的人赢  - 就这么定了
- Fastest one around the track wins. - It's on.
我会把你们逼出路线逼到撞墙
I'm gonna run you both off the road into a wall.
我会干掉你们
I'm gonna kill you.
我的天
Oh, my.
嘿 Chuck
Hey, Chuck.
能帮我把这些拿去干洗吗
Will you bring these to the dry cleaner for me?
告诉干洗店红印是血 棕色的印子是
Tell them the red stains are blood and the brown stains are...
就算是血吧
uh, let's say blood.
当然可以
Well, sure.
不劳烦你装在袋子里了
Don't even bother putting them in a bag.
我就用胳膊夹着吧
I'll just carry them in my arms.
嘿
Hey.
大胡子
Beard-o.
今天该从Charles家搬出来了
It's time for you to get out of Charles's house today.
等等 女士
Hang on, ma'am.
你没资格叫我做事
You don't tell me what to do.
这你就错了 小姑娘
Uh, that's where you're wrong, baby girl.
这片区归我管
I run this precinct.
瞧好了 Scully
Watch this. Scully!
- 给我睡觉  - 好的
- Go to sleep. - Okay.
你以为你能吓唬我
You think you can intimidate me?
没错
Yeah.
我当卧底的时候 "屠夫"Jimmy
When I was undercover, Jimmy "The Butcher"
用园艺剪把我的小脚趾剪了
cut off my little toe with garden shears
还让我吃了 以示忠诚
and made me eat it as a loyalty test.
我是经历过地狱的人
I've been through hell.
有什么了不起的
Big deal.
我在商场里的太阳镜柜台做了四年
I worked an a sunglass kiosk at the mall for four years.
所以我不仅经历过地狱
So not only have I been through hell,
还在地狱当过副经理
I was assistant manager there.
哦
Hmm.
你得从Chuckie家搬出来
You're gonna get out of Chuckie's house.
此外
And what's more,
还要把住一晚的钱给他
you're gonna pay him rent for the night you spent there.
- 好吧  - 还有一件事 宝贝儿
- Fine. - One more thing, babe.
你现在就谢谢我们两个
You're gonna thank us both right now.
- 谢谢你  - 不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
- 太厉害了  - 我就跟你说吧
- That was amazing. - Told you.
得像狼王一样镇住他
He just needed to be alpha'd.
还是说我太受气了让你看不过去 来保护我
Is that what happened, or did I just beta you into protecting me?
才不是
No. No.
不是这样的
That's not what happened.
不是你赢了
This is not your victory.
当然
Sure.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
你好啊
Hey, there.
还记得我吗
Remember me?
好诡异
So this is weird.
别想跑 你个马戏团人渣
Oh, no, you don't, circus trash.
我就知道
I knew it!
你一直都能走
You could walk the whole time!
猫也是帮凶 对不对
I was right about the cat accomplice too, huh?
猫呢
Now where's the cat?
都20年了 警长 猫可能死了
Been 20 years, Sarge. Cat's probably dead.
那我也得抓住它
I'm still bringing him in!
警长 你成功了
Well, Sarge, you did it.
接下来我们要怎么
Now how should we rub your sweet victory
羞辱6-5区的蠢货呢
in the 6-5's dumb faces?
送他们一箱老鼠
We could send them a box of rats,
因为他们就是老鼠
'cause they're rats.
或者往他们车上扔水气球
Or we could drop water balloons on their cars.
跟你说
You know what?
算了吧
I'm good.
我觉得我们不该这么做
I don't think we should do that.
确定吗 全都不做吗
Really? Any of it?
是啊 你为我做了这么多
Yeah, after everything you did for me...
鼓励我
encouraging me,
就算吓哭了
going out on that ledge
也爬上了窗台
even though you were scared to tears...
当时上面有空调
There was an air conditioner above us.
水滴到我眼睛里了
It was dripping water on my eyes.
说好不提了
We've been over this.
你为了破案整夜没睡
You stayed up all night to solve the case.
让我想起 我的生命中是有人关心着我的
It just reminded me that I have people in my life who cared about me.
我不知道为什么我要花这么多时间
I don't know why I'm spending so much time
向不关心我的人证明什么
trying to prove things to people who don't.
你在各种意义上都是一个"大"人
I guess you're a big man in more ways than one.
我本该想到的 但是 没有
Which I probably should have anticipated. But, did not.
- 你干什么了 Jake  - 老鼠 我送了老鼠
- What'd you do, Jake? - Rats... I did the rats.
我等不了了
I couldn't wait.
好好和老鼠玩吧 你们这群老鼠
Enjoy the rats, you rats.
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
哈哈哈 糟了 有一只跑到我这儿来了
Hahaha. Oh, no, one's coming for me!
电波字幕组 欢迎您的加入
官方网站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@电波字幕组